I mean,
我说
can't you swap out this sofa
你们家就不能换一个
for one with a higher back?
靠背高点儿的沙发吗
You wouldn't come over even if I did.
换了你也不来坐
Seriously,
你自己说
when was the last time you stopped by?
你都多久没来我家
Too far.
远
Too tired.
也累
And I'm too busy.
太忙了
You just don't want to come over.
你就是不想来
If you really want to come, just tell me.
你要真想来 一句话
I can send the driver to pick you up.
我让司机去接你嘛
I don't want to visit your place.
不来
The house is huge,
这房子虽然是大
but even if I stayed here forever,
但是住一辈子
it would never feel like mine,
也不是我的
and that's frustrating to see.
看着我还生气
Then you're staying here today,
那你今天就住这儿
alright?
好吧
I'll crash with you tonight.
我跟你睡
Give me a break.
去去去
Keep the flirtation for Haowen.
找你们家老贾撒娇去
Meng'an,
姐
have you noticed that
你有没有觉得
your estrogen levels are a bit unstable
怀孕之后啊
after pregnancy?
雌激素有点不稳定啊
I experienced a threatened miscarriage
我先兆性流产
and received treatment for it last night.
昨天晚上还保胎呢
How are you feeling now?
那你现在感觉怎么样啊
I'll take you
我带你去找
to my doctor.
我那个主治大夫
How can you keep your little one safe
你这东奔西跑的
with all this running around?
怎么保嘛
I don't want to fuss anymore.
不想折腾了
I just want to get some sleep.
就想好好睡一会儿
It's going to take some time for Dad
爸这个身体啊
to get better,
一时半会儿恢复不了
and your second child will be born soon.
你又马上要生二胎
I must take care of myself to
我得保重我自己
take responsibility for the entire family.
冲上去
Don't worry.
你放心
I'll do it after doing the month.
我出了月子 我来冲
You used to not want another child.
原来你不想要二胎
I didn't understand your reasons then,
我还不太能理解
but now...
现在
Do you want to give up the baby?
你不要了
I'm distraught about this.
心里头乱得慌
Come on. What's the big deal?
干吗呀 一惊一乍的
You didn't want a second child,
你原来也不是
did you?
不想要二胎吗
I'm sure.
我确定了
You're starting to get all hormonal.
你开始雌激素不稳定了
Relax,
不要作
relax, relax.
不要作 不要作
Eat some fruit. It'll help you chill out.
吃点水果 降降火
Let me worry for a bit.
你让我焦虑一会儿
One, two, three.
一 二 三
Nice job.
漂亮
Great.
好
Good, good.
可以 可以
Come on.
来
Stand a little farther back.
站远一点
One, two, three.
一 二 三
One...
一
Well done.
可以 很棒
Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
Mom.
妈妈
let's play together,
一起玩嘛
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
Yesterday afternoon,
昨天下午
I was upset with Xiongxiong's Grandma
我怪熊熊奶奶的时候
and said Jia's family
还说他们老贾家就是
was treating me like a baby-making machine
把我当成生育机器了
as I didn't want a second child,
根本不想生二胎
but they pressured me to have one.
他们非要让我生
Then,
结果
Dad went to the hospital that night.
晚上爸就进医院了
But today,
今天
I've changed my mind.
我突然改变主意了
What are you talking about?
说什么没头没尾的
Can't you get to the point?
能不能有点重点
The point is
重点就是
I no longer have to say that
我再也不说
others forced me to have a second child.
是别人逼我生二胎的了
It's my decision to have a second child.
现在是我自己要生二胎
Not only do I want to have a second child,
不但要生二胎
but if I'm physically able
生完之后
after giving birth to
如果我身体允许
my second child,
吃得消
I'll have a third child.
我还要生三胎
You're being willful again.
你 你这是又要作呀
That's not like you at all.
这可太不像你了啊
Meng'an,
姐
please keep the baby.
生吧
Let's have our second child together.
咱俩一起生
I'll take you
明天我就带你
to the hospital tomorrow.
去我那个医院
I'll make sure you have the best doctor
我给你配最好的医生
and the best room.
安排最好的病房
If you're admitted,
你住院保胎
you can keep the baby.
一定可以保下来
I don't need to be admitted.
还住院保胎
I have to go to the office and do my job.
我不上班 不工作呀
Come on.
行了
Don't be ridiculous.
别作了啊
Let's go to sleep.
睡觉吧
Dad will move to a new ward tomorrow.
爸明天换病房了
Meng'an, listen to me,
姐 你听我说
don't worry about that.
你这些不用操心
I'll take care of Dad.
爸那儿有我呢
There's Haowen
除了我之外还有老贾
and Li Lin too.
还有姐夫
We're all here for Dad.
我们这么多人呢
You should prioritize
你现在最应该操心的
the baby in your belly.
就是你肚子里的孩子
We have different situations.
我跟你情况不一样
I'm not in a position to have a child.
我是客观条件不允许
But don't worry.
不过你放心
Even if I cannot keep my baby,
就算我这个二胎没了
I promise to
我也会
treat your second child well,
好好对你的二胎的
as a good aunt
做到一个大姨
should.
该给的
Meng'an, don't give up.
姐 你别放弃啊
Let me show you a photo.
我给你看张照片
See,
你看
this is the photo.
就是这张照片
It got me thinking about how lucky
我看到的时候就在想
I am to be expecting my second child.
幸亏我怀了二胎
Otherwise,
不然的话
when Haowen and I get old,
等我和老贾老了
Xiongxiong will be alone.
就熊熊一个人
He would be so lonely
那他得多孤单啊
and under so much pressure,
他心理压力得多大呀
but if he had a sibling,
可是要是有个兄弟姐妹
they could lean on each other,
就可以共同扛事
just like you and me.
就像我跟你一样
Did Dad's illness
是不是爸生病这事
upset you?
刺激到你了
It makes you think
让你觉得
having a sibling is good.
有个姐妹也挺好
You can talk to each other
真有个什么事
and help each other
能有个商量
in tough times.
互相帮衬着
Dad's sudden illness
爸这次出事
took me by surprise
我心里特别慌
and caused me a lot of worry,
根本不知道该怎么办
but with your support
但是有你这个主心骨
and the whole family
还有我们这一大家子人
helping out,
各忙各的
I feel so much better.
我心里就特别踏实
Meng'an,
姐
please keep the baby,
你生吧
okay?
好不好
Didn't you ask me
你不是问我说
what Dad said to me
爸在监护病房里
in the ICU?
跟我说什么吗
Yeah,
是啊
but you didn't share anything.
那你也没说呀
Dad told me to keep the baby.
爸让我生
See...
你看
Since Dad advised you to keep the baby,
爸都让你生了
you should follow his guidance.
你得听话呀
It's not a matter of obeying Dad's words.
这是听话不听话的事吗
I initially didn't want a second baby,
以前是不想要
but now my body cannot keep it.
现在是保不住
It's not the same thing.
那能一样吗
Forget it.
算了 也别想了
Leave it to Darwin.
交给达尔文吧
Who's Darwin?
达尔文谁啊
Is he a doctor or something?
哪个大夫
Haha, just kidding.
逗你的
I know him.
我能不知道吗
Look at your eyes.
瞧你那眼神
The guy developed the theory of evolution,
进化论嘛
right?
对不对
Come here,
过来
The ER doctor said
急诊那个大夫说
that if I ended up
如果这个孩子
losing the baby,
保不住的话
it's just nature doing its thing
也是人类
with the survival of the fittest,
优胜劣汰的自然选择
so we shouldn't be too insistent.
不用强求
Why shouldn't we be insistent?
什么不用强求啊
We must be insistent on keeping the baby.
就要强求
Nowadays, science is very advanced,
现在科学多发达呀
so why not consider keeping the baby?
怎么保不住了
Get treatment to keep your baby,
你给我保二胎去
for god's sake.
真是
Do you know what Haowen said
你知道老贾当初
at the beginning?
是怎么说的
He said that if he ever gets old
他说 等他老了
and sick to the point of
万一得了绝症
being stuck in bed,
躺在床上动不了的时候
having only one child
如果只有一个孩子
would be really tough.
那压力多大呀
With two kids,
有两个孩子
they can make decisions collectively.
就可以一块儿做决定
Shall we pull the plug on Dad? Okay.
给老头子拔管不 拔
It's a good idea to discuss it,
有商有量的多好
right?
是吧
Haowen can be so dramatic.
这老贾也挺能作呀
You're right.
那是
Otherwise, I wouldn't be able to
不然我们能
live with him so peacefully.
过到一块儿去吗
You two are funny.
你俩就一块儿作吧
What's going on?
怎么了
I think the baby
这个孩子
overheard us
好像听到我们说话
and came early.
提前来了
What?
什么
What should we do, Meng'an?
怎么办呀 姐
It's not time yet.
还没到预产期呢
What if the baby
这孩子没长成
doesn't grow up?
怎么办呀
How come the baby doesn't grow up?
怎么没长成呢
When doing the ultrasound check,
你之前做超声检查
we saw that the baby was growing well,
不是照片都看见了吗
as shown in the ultrasound photos.
哪儿哪儿都长得挺好的
It's okay.
没事啊
Don't worry.
咱们不担心
It's a bit early,
虽然早产
but it's going to be okay.
但是肯定没问题的
Then stay here with me.
那你在这儿陪着我
I'm scared.
我害怕
I'll stay with you.
姐陪着你
I'm not going anywhere.
姐哪儿都不去
And...
还有
if something goes wrong
那要是一会儿
during labor,
如果出了什么问题
you must choose to save me.
你一定要保大啊
Xiongxiong can't live without me.
熊熊不能没有我
Don't prioritize saving the baby over me.
你不能保小 听到没有
It's gonna be okay.
不会有问题的
I've got your back.
姐保着你
Fetal heartbeat's dropping.
胎心下降
Ma'am, please get out of here.
家属赶紧出去
Excuse me, ma'am.
不好意思 家属
What?
什么
We're going to check.
我们要检查了
W- What's going on?
怎么 怎么了
So, what's up with her?
不是 这怎么回事啊
Excuse me.
不好意思啊
No.
不行
Can't I just stay here with her?
我不能在这儿陪着她吗
No, we need to proceed with the check.
不可以 我们要检查了
Meng'an, don't go.
姐 你不要走
No, no.
不行 不行
Easy does it, easy does it,
你听话 听话
let's do the check first.
检查一下
I'm at the door.
姐就在门口
You can spot me through the window.
窗户你能看见姐
Please take the check first.
你先检查啊
What's wrong with me?
怎么了
Mengxin, please take the check first.
心哪 你听话好好检查
I'm here for you.
姐在这儿呢
What actually happened to me?
怎么了呀
Take it easy.
别激动
What's happening?
怎么回事啊这
What does that mean?
怎么意思
Okay, just relax.
好 别着急啊
Meng'an.
姐
Haowen.
浩文
Is everything okay with Mengxin?
咋样了 心
She was doing okay just now,
刚 刚才还好好的呢
but the fetal heartbeat dropped suddenly,
那个胎心突然就报警了
and medical staff rushed me out.
大夫就把我给轰出来了
Mengxin,
心
Mengxin, I'm here for you.
心 我来了
Why is there an oxygen deficiency?
怎么会缺氧呢
I'm going to put you on oxygen.
我给你开下氧气啊
Take it easy.
你先稳定一下啊
The fetal heartbeat continues to drop,
现在胎心一直往下掉
and we're now preparing for a C-section.
准备剖腹产手术
No,
不是
no,
不是 这
why is this happening?
这怎么突然就这样了呀
I don't want a C-section.
我不要剖腹产
Go for it!
加油
Shut up!
加什么油啊
The fetus is at risk!
胎儿现在有危险
Why?
为什么啊
The fetal heartbeat is dropping.
胎儿胎心下降
We need to perform a C-section now.
要马上剖宫产手术
Please sign the consent form.
你们家属签个字吧
Don't sign it!
不许签字
Doctor,
大夫
doctor,
大夫啊
give me a little more time.
你再给我一点时间
I- I can do a natural birth.
我我我 我可以顺产的
Trust me, okay?
你相信我好不好
Don't yell, don't yell.
先不要喊 先不要喊
You can handle a C-section.
你可以的
You're a mom, aren't you?
你是妈妈 对吗
Stay strong.
要坚强
The baby will also do its best.
宝宝也会加油的
I previously had a natural birth.
我生过一个孩子了
They say the second one
她们说生二胎
will happen quickly and naturally.
生得可快了
Take it easy.
慢一点啊
Give me a little more time.
你再给我一点时间
I'll do it myself.
我自己顺
T- The second baby
二胎 二胎很快的
will arrive soon.
二胎很快就能生下来的
The baby's heartbeat is dropping,
胎心虽然在下降
but don't worry.
但没关系的
The C-section procedures
剖宫产技术
are very advanced and safe.
已经很成熟了
Let's work together
我们和孩子一起努力
as the baby is also cooperating, okay?
好吗
Meng'an,
姐
Haowen, help me!
老贾救我
I don't want a C-section!
我不要剖腹产
It is my wife's second delivery.
我们家这是二胎啊
Her previous labor was fast.
我们生得快
Can we try for a natural birth?
能让她顺产吗
Is a C-section necessary?
是必须手术吗
Yes, we must proceed with a C-section now.
马上
Sign the consent form.
签字
Haowen, don't sign it!
老贾 老贾你不要签字
Don't sign it!
你不许签字
I'll kill you if you sign!
你签字我弄死你
Haowen,
老贾
don't sign it!
不要签
I don't want a C-section!
我不要剖腹产
Don't sign it!
不许签字
Nowadays, C-section procedures
现在剖腹产手术
are highly advanced.
已经很成熟了
Don't worry. It's a safe option.
很安全的 没问题
Meng'an, you hear what she says.
姐 你听着她怎么说
She'll kill me if I sign it.
我要签字她会弄死我的
She can't even get out of bed.
她现在床都下不了
How can she kill you?
她怎么弄死你啊
Don't sign it.
你不许签字
I'll kill you if you do.
你签字我弄死你
I can't sign it, Meng'an.
我不能签 姐
She always wants to
心心一直心心念念
have the baby naturally.
要自己生 自己生
I can't decide for her.
这主我真做不了
How about
要不然
I call Mom for advice?
我给妈打一电话
Are you for real?
打什么电话呀
There's no time left.
这时候听谁的
Do you want to risk losing Mom and baby?
你是不是想一尸两命
Why is that?
这什么情况
Why does Mengxin need a C-section
这怎么还成了剖腹产
while I have to sign the consent form?
让我签字
Don't sign it!
不许签字
I'll kill you...
我弄死你
Here it is.
大夫
Thank you, doctor.
谢谢啊 大夫
Xu Meng'an,
许梦安
Jia Haowen...
贾浩文
I'm really stressed out.
压力好大啊
It's tough to see you
老婆受这么大的罪
going through so much pain.
我心里也不忍
Honey,
老婆
you've done so much for our family.
你给家里付出了这么多
I can't imagine how your little body
你那么娇小的身子
bears with the C-section surgery.
还挨了一刀
Honey,
老婆啊
for the rest of my life,
我这下半辈子
I promise to
我一定都得
do anything you say.
全部都得听你的
No matter how you throw your tantrums,
你再使性子 再发脾气
I'll bear with it.
我都会为你忍着
You're a real hero to our family.
你是咱们家的大功臣
I can't do anything without you.
你要不好我怎么办呢
Honey, please get well soon.
老婆 你快点好
I'm feeling overwhelmed.
我心理压力太大
Honey.
老婆
Why are you crying?
你哭什么哭
you're awake.
你醒了
That's great, honey.
太好了 老婆
When you're better,
等你好了
I'll take you on a trip.
我带你去旅游去
We'll go on a big cruise.
咱们坐着大游轮
We'll go wherever you want.
你想去哪儿去哪儿
I want to show you all the cool places
你没去的地儿
you have yet to visit
我全带你看
to show you the most breathtaking scenery.
最美的风光
We can also do some shopping,
我也带你去购物
and you can choose whatever you like.
你想买啥就买啥
I will purchase whatever you want.
要星星不给你买月亮
Honey,
老婆
you're so great.
老婆 你太伟大了
Seriously,
真的
you're a big hero to our family.
你是咱们家的大功臣
Honey, I mean it.
真的 老婆
You've been through so much,
你受了这么大的罪
and we all,
你看我们家
including me,
还有我贾浩文的
are grateful to you
幸福生活
for our happy life.
都是你给的
Honey,
老婆
don't cry.
老婆 别哭了
I always treated you like a princess,
我之前把你当公主
but now I want to treat you like a queen,
以后我把你当皇后
like an empress.
我要把你当女王
You mean everything
我们爷儿仨的命
to me and our two kids.
都是你给的
Honey,
老婆
from now on,
你以后说哪儿
your wish is my command.
我们就听哪儿
Seriously, I'm all yours.
真的 我全部都是你的
I want to go to work.
我想上班
No problem.
没问题
I remember you saying that you want to
你不是要上班
work and pursue the chairman position.
当董事长吗
I'm totally on board with that.
你去上班当董事长
I'll be a stay-at-home dad,
我在家当奶爸
cooking, making soup,
我每天给你做饭煲汤
and seeing you after work every day.
等着董事长下班
Pen that down.
立字据
What?
什么
Write down everything you just said.
把你刚才说的都写下来
Okay.
好
Let me know if there's anything else
还有什么
you'd like me to commit to,
你都说出来
and I'll jot them all down.
我全部给写下来
Honey.
媳妇
My wound hurts.
疼
Boohoo...
疼啊
I feel so bad for you, honey.
我媳妇疼
I brought Mom here.
我把妈接来了啊
She's looking after Mengxin.
在心心那儿呢
How's the baby?
孩子怎么样了
I don't know.
不知道啊
We have to trust science.
还是要相信科学的
I can't even see my daughter's face.
看不清长啥样
I'm not even sure if her eyes are open.
也不知道睁没睁眼
They say babies will resemble
都说第一眼看见谁
the first person they see.
长得像谁
How can you be sure
你怎么知道
the first person the baby sees
她第一眼
is not Mengxin?
看的不是心心呢
In the delivery room,
我们在产房里头
they always show the baby
孩子生出来
to the mother first,
都是要先抱给妈妈看的
so the first person your daughter saw
你们说的第一眼
could be the medical staff or Mengxin.
都不知道第几眼了都
Meng'an, your words made me feel better.
这我就放心了 姐
The first person my daughter saw
那肯定第一眼
must be her mom.
看的是心心
Keep an eye on your daughter.
看你闺女吧
Meng'an, please go home to get some rest.
姐 你回去休息吧
You haven't slept well in two nights.
你都折腾两晚上了
I'm good.
没事
Don't be ridiculous.
你说没事
You're pregnant.
那不还有孩子呢
Life is so fragile.
你看生命多脆弱的
We need to cherish it.
我们要爱护她
How about we go check out the baby?
要不我带你去看看孩子
Xin has
这心心现在
a boy and a girl now,
也算儿女双全了
which is a good thing.
这是好事
Yeah,
是
it's a good thing,
是好事
but Xin has gone through a lot of pain.
可我的心心太遭罪了
Congrats.
恭喜 恭喜
Thanks a lot.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢啊
See you around.
慢走 慢走
Come on, young ladies.
来来来 小姑娘
My daughter-in-law just had a baby girl.
我们家得了个大孙女
I got some gifts for you both.
一人一份 来来来
Congrats.
恭喜 恭喜
Thanks, thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
These treats
这喜糖 喜蛋啊
symbolize happiness.
多好的事啊
Thank you all for taking care of Mengxin.
谢谢你们多照顾啊
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Hey, girls,
小妹妹
come over here
来来来
and grab these gifts.
给你 给你 给你看
I've got candies and red eggs for you.
喜糖 喜蛋
I just became a grandma!
我们家大孙女
What a happy moment! Thanks!
好事啊 谢谢 谢谢啊
Feel free to try some.
大家吃
Don't be polite.
别客气啊
Sit still.
你坐着啊
Mrs. Jia, how's it going?
阿姨来了
Ah, Meng'an, you're here too.
大姐你也在哪
Wow, what wonderful news!
真是好事 好事啊
Xin now has a son and a daughter.
儿女双全 多好啊
Exactly, exactly.
是是是
Oh,
那个
Xin's asleep now.
心心啊 睡着了
You know,
然后那个
she's had a surgery,
这不是手术了吗
so it's best we let her get some rest.
让她好好休息休息
Yeah,
对对对
I'm here to see the baby.
我来看看孩子
The baby's in the observation room.
那个 孩子在观察室呢
Alright, I'll take a peek.
好 那我去看看啊
Go on.
快去吧
Go and see your dear granddaughter.
看看你大孙女
Thanks for everything.
你辛苦 你辛苦
No problem at all.
不辛苦 不辛苦
Off you go.
去吧 去吧
Mrs. Jia is thrilled to
阿姨也是高兴
have a granddaughter.
得了个大孙女
Try to understand her feelings.
你也理解 理解
I can't relate.
我没法理解
I don't get
我就不理解
how she can be so happy
我心心这么遭罪
when Xin went through so much pain.
她怎么能那么高兴
Having a C-section
这个剖腹产啊
is a
它也是一种
usual way of giving birth.
一种正常的分娩方式
Xin wanted to have a natural delivery.
她是要顺产的
The C-section is tough on the body
多伤身体啊
and can be debilitating.
伤元气
Come on.
你行了啊 差不多得了
I know you're worried about your daughter.
知道你是心疼闺女
Why do you look
你这脸色
so pale?
怎么也这么难看呢
You're always crying.
你老在这儿哭
How can I look good?
我能好看哪
Well,
不是 你
you'd better go home and get some rest.
你早点回去休息
I'll stay here and keep an eye on Xin.
我在这儿守着心心
Are you sure you want to stay her
你守着她
If she wakes up and sees you like this,
心心一醒过来看你这样
you'll both end up in tears.
你俩还不得抱头痛哭啊
Then I won't cry.
那我 我不哭
I won't cry.
我不哭了
Don't cry.
咱不哭了啊
It's a good thing.
这是个好事
It's crucial that when Xin wakes up,
心心一醒来的时候
you greet her with a smile.
你得对她笑
Come on, you can do it.
听话啊
Okay, you can head home.
你你你 回去吧
You stay here with her.
你在这儿陪着她
I'll check Dad first.
我先去看一眼我爸
Take care.
乖啊
I'll make sure to smile.
笑
She looks so tiny
感觉她好小啊
and delicate,
好精致呀
all fleshy,
看上去肉肉的
pink,
粉粉的
and soft.
软软的
Like a doll.
跟个洋娃娃似的
To me, she looks like a caterpillar.
我看像毛毛虫
You know nothing,
你懂什么呀
kid.
小屁孩
Is this my little sister?
这是我妹妹吗
Could it be a mistake?
不会错了吧
No way.
怎么可能
I've seen your baby pictures.
我看过你刚出生的照片
She looks just like you.
跟你挺像的
I look good.
我好看着呢
That's how babies look.
刚出生小孩都长这样
No way.
不可能
I was definitely better looking than her.
我肯定比她好看
Where is she?
哪儿呢
Grandma.
奶奶
Hi, Grandma.
奶奶好
Hi, grandson.
宝贝
Mom, look!
妈妈妈 看
Which one is she?
哪一个
That one is your granddaughter.
就是咱们家的小宝宝
She's so adorable,
好可爱呀
with fair skin
好白 好白
and big eyes
眼睛好大
like yours.
眼睛像你的
Mom, her eyes don't look like mine.
妈 哪像我
They look like Xin's. Xinxin is beautiful.
像心心 心心漂亮
She'd be plain if she looks like me.
像我可完蛋了
She looks beautiful.
好看 好看 好看
Do you think so, too?
好看哈
Yeah.
好看
You now have a son and a daughter. Great!
太好了 儿女双全哪
Your dad
你说你爸爸在天之灵
would be happy
也会祝福你的
and bless you from above.
也会高兴的
Mom, you're so blessed.
妈 是您有福
I never thought
我都没想到
I'd have a little princess baby.
我能生一个公主宝宝哈
The whole family is so fortunate.
全家人都有福
Have you picked a name yet?
起名了没有啊
No rush, Mom.
这不着急 妈
I'll come up with a good name later.
回头我起个好名字
You know,
那起名 起名啊
the more casual the name,
起得越平常越好
the better.
越好养活
We used to call you Dark Blob,
你小的时候叫黑煤球
and you didn't even have a proper name
你一直到小学
until you started school.
才给你起大名呢
But come on, Mom,
妈 你别太激动
it's not that old of a time.
那都什么年代了
Dark Blob? Stop kidding.
还黑煤球呢 什么
How about letting Xiongxiong pick a name?
叫咱家熊熊起名怎么样
Xiongxiong,
熊熊
your sister's so cute.
你看你妹妹这么可爱
I bet you can pick a good name for her.
你给起个名
Me?
我起
Mom, what a good name he could choose?
妈 他能起什么
He's just a kid.
他还是个孩子呢
Yeah, he's only in first grade.
就是 他才一年级
What if he picks a name
他要起什么
like Ultraman?
奥特曼那种怎么办啊
I won't. Anyway, she's my sister.
那不能够 这是我妹妹
I already have a name for her.
我已经想好了
I want to call her
她叫
Little Watermelon.
小西瓜吧
That's adorable.
这好 这好
I think this name isn't a good choice.
小西瓜
Watermelon is sweet
西瓜甜哪
and pink,
粉嫩粉嫩的
and it would be adorable to
你看
nickname a girl Little Watermelon.
女孩叫小西瓜多好啊
Great!
厉害 厉害
Xiongxiong, you've done a great job
熊熊 你真厉害
naming your sister.
给妹妹起的名儿真好
After counting down from three to one,
我数三二一
let's say Little Watermelon.
咱们一起喊小西瓜
Okay, keep the voice lower.
好的 小声啊
Three, two, one.
三 二 一
Little Watermelon.
小西瓜
Hello, Mr. Li.
喂 厉总
How's your day?
你好
It's me, Zhou.
是我 小周
Did you check out
上次我给您发
the financial product
那理财产品
I sent you last time?
您看了吗
Our real estate company
我们地产公司
is super secure and much more reliable
比外面那些小金融公司
than those smaller finance companies.
稳妥多了
We invest in these products ourselves,
我们自己都买产品呢
so you can trust that they're reliable.
特靠谱
Feel confident when you buy products
交给我们华謃地产呢
from our Huaxing Real Estate Co.
您就放一百个心吧
Looks like everyone's quite busy today.
看来大家今天都很忙啊
Are the pre-sale results looking good
第一次对客户摸底
for your first client surveys?
预售情况怎么样
On my end,
我这边呢
several clients have
好几个客户
shown strong interest in our product.
都表现出非常高的兴趣
Right.
对啊
Selling a house
我们这种房屋销售
can take a long time to close a deal
周期时间太长
because people don't buy houses often.
谁也不会频繁买房子
But selling financial products
但这金融产品
is a whole different ball game.
真是不一样啊
It seems like everyone
看来大家今天
did well in today's pre-sale.
预售情况都不错啊
Keep up the good work.
大家都尽心了啊
Unfortunately,
但不像有些人啊
someone has a ton of
手里握着一大堆
high-quality clients.
优质客户
But she can't even
一张理财单子
close a single financial deal.
都开不出来
Well, you all get back to work now.
行 大家各忙各的
You, come here with me.
你跟我过来一下
Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真
look at everyone else
你看看大家
working hard to make sales,
都在冲销售业绩呢
and you're not even making a phone call.
你连个电话都不打
Is it appropriate for you to do that?
合适吗
Don't you want to
你不想让工资
increase your paycheck?
流水好看吗
I'm trying to help you.
我这是在帮你啊
I understand, Mr. Qian. Thanks.
我知道钱总 谢谢你啊
Actually,
其实
I'm investing in a securities
我现在自费参加了一个
training course out of my own pocket.
证券从业培训班
I believe that once I
我想着等我对这方面
have a better grasp of this area,
有了更多的了解
I'll find it easier to
那以后做这方面
sell financial products later.
不就更加地得心应手吗
Come on, Chen Wanzhen.
不是 陈婉真
Don't try to
你能不能别在我这儿
fool me.
耍花腔
You have a degree
你的学历
associated with this field,
就是学这个专业
so why are you still undergoing training?
你还培训什么培训啊
To be honest,
那我跟你说实话吧
I don't want to sell financial products.
我不想卖理财
Because I believe
因为我觉得
this practice
这是对我客户资源的
wastes my clients' resources
一种消耗
and is irresponsible.
也是一种不负责任
Wanzhen,
婉真
it's great that
你对客户负责没错
you prioritize your clients' interests.
非常好
However, it's also essential to
但是偶尔也得
strengthen your relationships with them.
拉近拉近情感吧
How about
要不然这样
organizing another social event
你再组织一次邀请会
and inviting all your clients?
你把你这些客户都请来
We can use this opportunity to
咱们就简简单单地
casually introduce
介绍一下
our company's financial products
咱们公司的理财产品
without making the gathering too formal.
不是生硬的啊
It will also improve
这样还能拉近一下
your connection with your clients.
客户之间的感情
Is that okay with you?
你觉得呢
No.
不行
There you are.
来了
How's Dad?
爸怎么样了
Today, he was able to
今天 这手脚啊
move arms and legs.
能动了
The doctor said
大夫说
that's the best thing that could happen.
这就是最好的情况了
He'll recover slowly
就这么慢慢地恢复
and do rehab
慢慢地做复健
until the blood in his brain
等他这脑部的血
clears up.
收干净了就会好
There won't be any after-effects,
后遗症也不会有什么
but the main thing is to
主要就是要预防
prevent a second stroke.
二次得中风
Good.
好
How are you today?
你怎么样 今天
I'm good.
我 挺好的
Come over here and take a seat.
来来 你 你坐下说
I'm not sitting down.
我不坐
Come outside with me.
你跟我出来
I need to talk to you about something.
我有事跟你商量
Listen,
是这样
I've been thinking about it
我想好了
and decided to
这个孩子
have the baby
我们还是生吧
as long as my body allows.
我是说能保住的情况下
Honey,
老婆
are you making
你做这个决定
this decision
是为了给咱爸
to encourage Dad?
一个鼓励吗
Not really.
也不全是
I see that
我在爸身上
there's nothing that we can't overcome
好像就看不到什么
in Dad.
困难是克服不了的
Yeah,
对
as long as we stick together
只要咱们一家人
as a family,
能在一起
there's nothing
没什么困难
we can't get through.
咱们克服不了
But having this baby
但是我们
might come with
生这个孩子的代价
a hefty price tag.
可能会很高
My health,
包括我的身体
my job,
我的工作
how we raise this child
还有将来
in the future,
我们对这个孩子的抚养
our overall quality of life,
还有我们的生活质量
and our standard of living
和水平
could all be impacted.
可能都会受到影响
But since
但我想着
we are a family,
一家人嘛
we can handle challenges together.
那就是一家人了
This little one
孩子来的时候
didn't come into our lives
不是因为谁家条件好
because we're better off.
才来的
We can't just
我们也不能
abandon him
因为这样的原因
because of that.
就不要他了
They all say that a child
人说
can thrive no matter how you raise them,
孩子怎么养都能活
so I think that
我就想着
if,
如果
and I mean if,
我是说如果啊
the problems
我们之前担心的
we've been worried about
那些问题
really happen,
真的出现了
we can sell
我就想把那个
the new house we bought
新买的房子卖了
and live together
然后咱们一家人
in the current one.
就住在现在的那个家里
But as long as we're happy,
但是只要是高兴快乐的
the life
是不是就是
is sweet.
美满幸福的呀
Do you think so?
你觉得行吗
Yes.
行
Let's bear the burden together.
那咱俩一起扛啊
Sure.
扛
Mom.
妈
I'm here,
妈在呢
Xin.
心心
The wound hurts.
疼
You've endured so much.
心心受罪了
I know. I know it.
妈知道 妈知道
Hugs for you.
妈抱抱 妈抱抱
Mom.
妈
Lin,
姐夫
I'm so happy.
我太高兴了 姐夫
I've become a father once again.
我又当爹了
I have a daughter.
我生了个闺女
Congrats!
同喜同喜
Thanks, Lin!
姐夫谢谢分享
Thanks!
姐夫
Are those red eggs and candies?
喜糖 喜蛋
Yes, they are.
红蛋 红糖
Let me try some.
吃一个
My mom prepared them. Go ahead.
妈准备的 快来快来
Thank you.
谢谢姐夫分享
Help yourself.
来来来
Lin, you know what?
姐夫 你都不知道啊
Holding my chubby son in my arms
我看生熊熊的时候
as a dad for the first time didn't
大胖小子抱怀里
bring me as much joy as it does now.
我都没有这么高兴
My daughter is the sweetest,
姑娘是小棉袄 小情人
born with fair skin and cute chubbiness.
生下来白白胖胖
She has these big, beautiful eyes
大眼睛忽闪忽闪
and looks exactly
长得跟我们家心心
like Xin.
一模一样
She's a carbon copy of her mother.
护士都说了
but comment on how gorgeous she was.
姑娘太美 太漂亮
Lin,
姐夫
why are you even more excited than I am?
你怎么比我还激动
Haowen,
浩文
get ready to enjoy
等着吃姐夫的喜糖
the treats I'll bring over to celebrate.
喜蛋吧
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
An and I have made the final decision.
我们定了
We've decided to keep the baby.
我们决定生
Wait, wait.
等等等 等等等
Shouldn't we have a big hug to celebrate?
不值得拥抱吗
Hold on.
不不不
Give me one moment.
等下 让我缓缓
Let me think about it.
让我倒倒
Why do you need to think about that?
倒什么
Do you
你在
have a say in your family's stuff?
在你们家说话算数吗
Of course, I have a say.
我怎么不算数啊
What's on your mind?
你怀疑什么啊
Your family's decisions constantly change.
你们家老变
Is everything set in stone?
这事定稿了吗
It's final.
定稿了
Lin,
姐夫
listen,
我跟你说 姐夫
you should be like me
你一定要跟我一样
and have a daughter.
生个小棉袄
Wait, Lin,
等一下 姐夫
your family already has a daughter.
你家有一个小棉袄了
You must have a son this time.
你要给我生一个军大衣
Girl and boy,
儿女双全
Lin,
姐夫
double joy.
好上加好
Double joy.
好上加好 姐夫
Well, chill.
这样啊 先冷静
We've made our decision.
这个事啊 就这么定了
But
但是呢
But let's keep it down low for now.
我们不往外面去说
Meng'an needs to
梦安这个身体啊
care for herself
还需要调
and the baby,
这个胎啊 还要安
so let's not spill the beans, okay?
明白吗
Wait,
你等等 等等
will you two change your minds?
你们家还会变化呀
Don't stress.
变什么化呀
The decision is final.
不变了
We're going to make this work.
要让好事落地啊
Make this work.
好事落地
I can't believe it, Lin.
太开心了 姐夫
Girl and boy...
咱们儿女双
Please lower your voice.
请安静一点
You're outside the ward rooms.
这里是病房
Girl and boy,
好上加好
double joy.
好事成双
I'm so happy.
我太高兴了
Let's pick it up.
捡一下吧
Yunjie.
云阶
Why aren't you in bed yet?
怎么还不睡觉啊
I'm waiting for you two.
等你俩呢
I want to talk to you.
想跟你俩谈谈
Take a seat.
坐吧
Sit here.
坐
What do you want to talk to us about?
谈什么呀
Dad, you go first.
爸 你先说吧
What should I say first?
我先说什么
We already talked about that.
咱俩商量好的呀
You know,
就那事
it's that thing.
那个事啊
I smell a plot.
有阴谋
No way,
没有
there's no plot.
怎么可能有阴谋呢
I don't say it, you say it yourself.
我不说 要说你说
Dad,
爸
I can't believe you!
你真
Fine, I'll just say it.
我说
Mom,
妈
you should keep the baby
你肚子里的宝宝要生
because I really want a little sister.
因为我想有个妹妹
Dad's on my side too,
老爸他也支持
but he dares not say anything.
只是他不敢说
I don't care.
我不管
I'm your daughter,
反正我是你女儿
and you can't stop me.
你也不能把我怎么样
Now the ball's in your court,
现在压力给到你这边了
so let's see what you do.
看你什么态度
I've said my piece.
我说完了
You've got some nerve.
你现在挺敢哪
You dare to talk to me like that.
这么没大没小了
I'm part of this family.
我也是家里的一员嘛
This baby
这个孩子
will be my sister.
将来是我的亲妹妹
I need to
我肯定要
make my point.
发表一下我的态度
Why do you think the baby
你怎么就觉得
I'm expecting is a girl?
一定是个妹妹呢
It just has to be a girl, that's it.
一定就是妹妹
But what if it ends up being a boy?
万一是弟弟呢
No way.
绝对不可能
What's your take on it?
你说
Well, for me,
我
I'm okay with either a boy or a girl.
弟弟妹妹都行
Mom, I really want a sister.
妈 我真的很想要妹妹
Today,
我今天
I saw Xiongxiong's little sister.
看见熊熊的妹妹了
She looked so adorable and light-skinned,
特别可爱 白白嫩嫩的
and my heart melted once I saw her.
我心都要化了
Mom,
妈
please keep the baby.
你就生吧
I can't get
我有点想不明白
why you're so eager to
为什么你一定
have a sister.
掉进妹妹的坑里面
It's because I am her big sister.
因为我是她姐呀
We share a telepathic bond.
我俩有心电感应的
You're my child,
你还是我闺女呢
so why can't you use that telepathic bond
要不然你感应一下
to tell me if I'm going to keep the baby?
我到底是生还是不生啊
You'll keep the baby,
生
will you?
生吗
I'm the one who is expecting the baby.
生孩子的是你妈
Why are you asking your dad?
问你爸干啥
I promise
我保证
I'll act mature from now on
我以后一定会懂事的
and won't get you in trouble.
绝不给你惹麻烦
You act too mature.
我看你就是懂太多了
Listen,
听妈说啊
about having a second child,
关于生二胎这个事呢
I personally
其实我主观意识上
want to have one.
是想生的
But I've always been
但是一直是
unable to do so.
客观条件不允许
Lately, we have experienced a lot.
最近家里出了这么多事
Luckily, they have
但是这些事呢
taken a turn
好像又往好的地方
for the better.
发展了
Your grandpa has regained consciousness,
你外公也醒了
and your aunt has had her second child.
你小姨二宝也生了
I've always felt that
我老觉着
this baby
是不是冥冥之中
is meant to
老天爷
be a part
还是想让这个孩子
of our family.
来咱们家呢
So what's holding you back? Let's keep it.
那还说什么呀 生吧
Are you sure?
生啊
Yes.
生
Alright,
行
let's keep the baby.
那就生吧
Mom, I love you!
妈妈 我爱你
Be careful.
动作小一点啊
Your mom's pregnant.
你妈还保着胎呢
Little Grape, my bad.
小葡萄 对不起
I didn't mean it.
姐姐不是故意的
My dear sister!
妹妹
Dad, is Mom still sleeping?
爸 老妈还睡着呢
Your mom's been exhausted these two days.
你妈妈这两天太累了
Let her get some more sleep.
让她多睡会儿
Okay.
好
Who's there?
谁啊
Jing,
姐
what brings you here?
你怎么就来了呢
Why can't I be here?
我怎么就不能来呢
Where's Mong'an?
梦安呢
She's sleeping.
她 睡着呢
Let her get some rest.
让她好好休息
Auntie,
姑
did you know my mom is pregnant?
你是知道我妈怀孕了吗
Yeah,
对呀
that's excellent news.
这么大的喜事
I should be there, shouldn't I?
姑得来 对吧
If your aunt gets wind of any news,
你大姑要知道了
the whole world will know about it.
全世界就都知道了
It's fine if the whole world finds out.
全世界都知道了也没关系
But she'll scold
但是她会批评我们
and lecture us
会教育我们
and take charge.
会支配我们
Go inside and brush your teeth.
进去刷牙去
Jing,
我说姐
I mean,
我的意思是
you should have informed me
你来也跟我打个招呼
so I could have picked you up.
我好去接你嘛
It's fine.
不用
The morning bus is less crowded.
早班车人少
Okay,
行
I'll go wake up Mong'an.
我去叫梦安起床啊
Let her get a little more sleep.
让她多睡会儿
J-
大
Jing...
姐
Li Lin,
李临
your father-in-law had a stroke,
你岳父中风
your sister-in-law had premature birth.
小姨子早产
Why didn't you tell me about
这么大的事
the big things that happened?
你为什么不告诉我
Jing,
姐
it's none of your business.
关你什么事啊
She...
她
it's about Meng'an's family.
人家梦安家的事 她
We're family, aren't we?
咱不是一家人吗
Meng'an's family issues
梦安家的事
are also my concern.
就是咱们家的事
Families are supposed to
一家人
help each other.
总得相互帮衬吧
Do you still consider me as your sister?
你心里还有你姐姐吗
Yes, of course,
有
we do.
肯定是有的
Please don't be upset.
姐 你别生气啊
We had plenty of help on hand,
之前我们人手也是够
so we didn't feel the need to bother you.
倒得过来 就没跟你说
Furthermore,
再说了
you have to look after
你不是还得
your husband.
照顾姐夫呢吗
Why do I need to look after him?
我照顾他干吗呀
I want to take care of you.
我现在就想照顾你
You're pregnant,
你不是怀孕了吗
so let me lend you a hand
我就想给你搭一把手
so you can take a break.
让你能歇歇 这不好吗
Our family matters all settled in now.
我们现在都安顿好了
My father has been
我爸已经
moved to the general ward.
转到普通病房了
Xin has given birth and will be going to
心心也生了
the care center in two days.
过两天就去月子中心了
Thanks to Lanxiang,
之前能倒得过来
we've managed to stabilize.
还是多亏了兰香姐的
You're so kind to send her to help us.
那还是你让她来的呢
I really appreciate it, Jing.
我还得谢谢你呢 大姐
Come on,
你看你
don't mention it.
说到哪儿去了
Lanxiang briefed me on the situation.
这个情况兰香跟我说了
The three of you
你们仨
are taking turns
现在轮流倒班
to look after your dad now, aren't you?
照顾你爸 对吧
Now I'm here. You can take a break.
我来了 你休息
I will take care of your dad
我们仨倒班照顾你爸
in your place, okay?
怎么样
What...
那
What about your husband?
那我姐夫呢
Why should I worry about him?
我管他干吗呀
He's got his apprentice to look after him.
他不有他徒弟照顾他吗
You're the most important one
你现在
in our family now.
是我们家最大的宝贝
I'll make sure to take good care of you.
我得把你照顾好
Don't worry. I've taught Lanxiang
你放心 兰香那几招啊
how to care for patients.
还是跟我学的
I'm sure that I'll do better than her.
我肯定比她做得好
Sure thing.
那是
Meng'an,
梦安
I heard from Lanxiang that
我听兰香说你
you've had prenatal care for a while.
前一段时间一直在保胎
Yeah.
保胎呢
Come on.
来
Guess what I brought you?
我给你带什么了
She can't take medication, Jing.
她不能乱吃药 姐
What do you know?
你懂什么呀
Who said it's medicine?
谁说这是药了
It's nutrition.
这是营养品
It was your grandfather's secret recipe.
这是你爷爷祖传的秘方
It's what you drank
你怀云阶的时候
when you were pregnant with Yunjie.
喝的就是这个方子啊
My husband made it
你姐夫啊
with great care.
精心配制
I boiled it all night
我昨天晚上
last night.
熬了一晚上才熬成的
Let me heat a packet
我现在
for you right now.
赶紧给你热一包
Drinking it can
喝了
reduce stress and protect the fetus.
咱就安神保胎
H- H-
救 救
Help!
救 救个命啊
Run!
跑吧